{
    "id": "0d164d9b61cc483490c3a839605b57b1",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I could not believe my eyes, when I ……………………. him there.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to talk about the earlier of two past actions. When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too should be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "spot",
                "spotted",
                "had spotted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "51f53da57b9b4e57adcd5d4effe469b8"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where she ……………………….. is still a mystery.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "disappeared",
                "disappear",
                "disappears"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d47ea55f41c8438fa50597f952dec388"
        },
        {
            "question": "What he did ………………….. me.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "shocked",
                "had shocked",
                "is shocking"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "707db89e54b843218af4cc76cca60bfb"
        },
        {
            "question": "How did he react when you ……………………….. him red handed?",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too should be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "caught",
                "have caught",
                "catch"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b92317103b75473eb736a6c0d7008e20"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………. a lot of money.",
            "description": "Has got shows possession.",
            "answers": [
                "has got",
                "got",
                "had got"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "136cdacb82fd48f39772282a79fee1a6"
        },
        {
            "question": "She was angry so I …………………….. nothing.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too should be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "said",
                "had said",
                "have said"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "942bc7ea96c34d3185f495a789114026"
        },
        {
            "question": "The man ran away as soon as he ……………………. the tiger.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too should be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "sees",
                "saw",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "fa6ab0ca06974f81902ed617b2896d1b"
        },
        {
            "question": "What …………………… you do if you lost your job?",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "can"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "332d0e98ecbd45a6b23fb8ee0685a485"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ………………………. me before borrowing my car?",
            "description": "Should have + past participle is used to criticize people for not doing things. ",
            "answers": [
                "should have asked",
                "should be asking"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2d87e62d37c44d628b36d7afac2c5e26"
        },
        {
            "question": "If they had taken him to hospital, he …………………………. saved.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and could / would have been + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "could be",
                "can be",
                "could have been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1434b91b59c040248a01ae00efadd57e"
        },
        {
            "question": "Though I tried hard, I …………………….. solve the puzzle.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "cannot",
                "could not",
                "did not"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "498f8e0f79dc4b2cac1ca073c60bcbaa"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………. him but he didn’t turn up.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to talk about the earlier of two actions however, in some cases, the simple past is also possible with the same meaning. ",
            "answers": [
                "invited",
                "have invited",
                "had invited"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5a1bdb44874644e684a7ea3dff0bc169"
        }
    ]
}